#### **Guénolé FICHE**

10, rue Alfred de Musset 91120 Palaiseau, France guenole.fiche@gmail.com (+33) 6 51 36 24 77

www.linkedin.com/in/Guenole-Fiche

https://g-fiche.github.io/ https://github.com/g-fiche



26 years old

# PhD Student in computer vision - CentraleSupelec Anticipated graduation date: 10/24 (Available from 09/24)

My research focuses on Computer Vision and Deep Learning. I work on 3D human pose and shape estimation from images and videos, with a focus on weakly-supervised methods (generative models, self-supervised learning).

#### **Education**

•	Since 2021	PhD student in computer vision – CentraleSupelec (France)
		Subject: Learned latent representations for human mesh recovery
		Keywords: Pytorch, (D-)VAE, VQ-VAE, MAE, digital humans, SMPL, 3D vision
•	2016-2021	Mathematic Engineering department – INSA Rouen Normandie (France)
		Keywords: AI, Machine Learning, optimization, statistics
•	June 2016	Science Baccalaureate – European section – Graduate with High Honors

### Work experience

•	2023	Visiting PhD Student - Institut de robòtica i informàtica industrial (Spain)
		Exchange in the "Perception and manipulation" group
•	2022 - 2023	Tutorial Assistant – INSA Rennes (France)
		Geometry tutorials for second year students of engineering (Curves and surfaces, integrals)
•	2021	Deep Learning 6 months internship – Polynom (France)
		Multi-object detection and tracking
		Keywords: Python, Pytorch, YOLOv5, optical flow, Kalman Filter, GPS, orthophotos,
•	Summer 2020	NLP 3 months internship – Case Law Analytics (France)
		Natural Language Processing methods applied to automated analysis of legal texts
		Keywords: Python, Tensorflow, BERT, Regex, k-means, ACP, similarity, NLI
•	Summer 2019	Deep Learning 3 months research internship – University of British Columbia (Canada)
		Exploring the Application of Machine Learning for Physical Problem
		<b>Keywords:</b> Python, Tensorflow, Deep Learning, LSTM, ML for physics, composite materials
•	2019-2021	Sales manager and project leader - Junior Enterprise of the INSA Rouen (France)

#### **Publications**

- Fiche, G., Leglaive, S., Alameda-Pineda, X., & Moreno-Noguer, F. (2024). MEGA: Masked Generative Autoencoder for Human Mesh Recovery. https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.18839
- Fiche, G., Leglaive, S., Alameda-Pineda, X., Agudo, A., & Moreno-Noguer, F. (2023). VQ-HPS: Human Pose and Shape Estimation in a Vector-Quantized Latent Space. arXiv preprint arXiv:2312.08291.
- Fiche, G., Leglaive, S., Alameda-Pineda, X., and Séguier, R. 2023. Motion-DVAE: Unsupervised learning for fast human motion denoising. In Proceedings of the 16th ACM SIGGRAPH Conference on Motion, Interaction and Games (MIG '23).
- Fiche, G., Sevestre, V., Gonzalez-Barral, C., Leglaive, S., and Séguier, R. 2023. SwimXYZ: A large-scale dataset of synthetic swimming motions and videos. In Proceedings of the 16th ACM SIGGRAPH Conference on Motion, Interaction and Games (MIG '23).

#### **Skills**

Languages: English (TOEIC test: 965) and Spanish (Advanced)

**Programming:** Python (Pytorch and Tensorflow) - Notions of: R, Matlab, Java, C, C++, SQL Areas of expertise: Deep learning (VAE, dynamic models, probabilistic AI), 3D computer vision

Generative models, weakly-supervised and self-supervised learning

Virtual humans, pose and shape estimation, human motion.

Courses: Machine Learning (Coursera) – Andrew Ng, Stanford

English for research, Research communication ethics, Bayesian Data fusion

Summer schools: Generative Modeling Summer School, Copenhagen, June 2023

Sport and IA, Antibes, October 2022

## Hobbies Other experiences

Sports: Tennis, Volleyball, Running...

Music: Musical education and guitar practice

Music studies section – INSA de Rouen

Language learning: Hindi

2022 Reviewing

ECCV, CVPR, The Visual Computer, TMM...

July 2018 European Solidarity Corps - Spain

Tourism information counsellor

**2018-2019** Volunteer Tutoring in mathematics

Help in mathematics for INSA students